motorolasolutions.com 2018-11-11

# Privacy Statement - Motorola Solutions

Motorola Solutions ("MSI") recognizes privacy and security as being concerns for most individuals accessing the Internet, including our customers. This Statement describes how Motorola Solutions collects, uses and safeguards information you provide when using [www.motorolasolutions.com](http://www.motorolasolutions.com/);  [airwavesolutions.co.uk](https://www.airwavesolutions.co.uk/home/);  [avigilon.com](http://avigilon.com/);  [kodiakptt.com](http://kodiakptt.com/);  [spillman.com](http://spillman.com/);    
[vestapublicsafety.com](http://vestapublicsafety.com/); and [waveoncloud.com](http://waveoncloud.com/) (our "web sites") in accordance with the relevant legislation for the countries in which such data is being processed. By using our web sites, you consent to the collection and use of your information by Motorola Solutions as set forth in the policy currently in effect. Any changes to this Statement will be posted on our web sites. Motorola Solutions will take appropriate and reasonable measures to inform you when we update this Statement, consistent with the significance of the changes we make and will obtain your consent to any material changes if and where this is required by applicable data protection laws. You can see when this Statement was last updated by checking the date displayed at the bottom of this Statement.

The data controller(s) of the personal information collected via the Motorola Solutions Intranet website(s) are registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office and are as listed below:

  * Motorola Solutions UK Limited                           Registration Number Z7243174
  * Motorola Solutions Services Limited                  Registration Number Z1847582
  * Motorola Solutions, Inc                                       Registration Number Z9428854
  * Trustee(s) of the Motorola Pension Scheme      Registration Number Z8546778

Motorola Solutions has adopted a set of binding corporate rules ("BCRs"), which have been approved by the appropriate Data Protection Regulators in the European Union, effective May 2, 2013. For a copy of Motorola Solutions BCRs [click here](http://www.motorolasolutions.com/content/dam/msi/docs/business/_documents/static_files/Motorola_Solutions_BCR_Policy.pdf). The BCRs ensure that personal data of covered individuals in the European Union is protected while being processed by any of MSI's affiliates around the world. The information commissioner's Binding Corporate Rules Authorization is available at the [ICO UK Website](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/binding-corporate-rules/).

This Statement of privacy practices discloses the privacy policy for Motorola Solutions' public web sites. It applies to web sites operated by or on behalf of Motorola Solutions, Inc. and its applicable world-wide affiliated companies and subsidiaries.

For purposes of this Privacy Statement, the list of relevant entities can be found [here](https://www.motorolasolutions.com/content/dam/msi/docs/about-us/privacy/eu_entity_list.pdf).

### Data Collected

**What personal information is collected?**

**Product and Services**  
When a visitor places an order with us, Motorola Solutions may collect personal information about you, including name, title, company, address, email address, phone numbers and, in rare instances, other categories of personal information, such as payment card information, driver's license numbers, social security numbers (or equivalent national identification numbers) and date of birth.

  * **Specific Product Privacy Practices  
**The following notices explain specific privacy practices with respect to certain Motorola Solutions products, solutions and services that you may use:

**Marketing**  
We may ask you for and collect personal information at other times, including when you enter a sweepstakes or contest; participate in a promotion or marketing campaign sponsored by Motorola Solutions or one of its business partners; when you want to find out about service offered in your area; when you complete surveys or other questionnaires; when you participate in a user forum or blog hosted by Motorola Solutions or one of its business partners; when you send an email to Motorola Solutions.

Motorola Solutions (and our Service Providers) may also collect information made publicly available through third-party platforms such as social media websites, online databases, or directories or other legitimately obtained information. This information may be governed by the privacy notice(s) provided by the third party at the time of collection.

If you do not wish to receive marketing communications you can opt out by visiting the Communications Preference Center. After you opt out, we will not send further promotional emails, but we may continue to contact you to the extent necessary for the purposes of any services that you have requested.

**Recruitment**  
We will collect personal information when you express interest in employment with Motorola Solutions, whether directly or via an agent or recruiter (speculatively or in response to any ad on the basis of our legitimate interest to recruit new employees or contractors). Data that may be collected by Motorola Solutions or one of its business partners includes, but is not limited to, names, contact information, CV or resume, date of birth, performance management  information, compensation information, race and ethnic origin.  

**Other Information Collection**  
We may also collect personal information when you engage in other activities on our web sites. Our web server logs collect the domain names of visitors to our web sites. This information is aggregated to measure number of visits, average time spent on a Motorola Solutions web site, pages viewed and web site usage information. We use this information to measure the use of our sites and to improve the content of our sites. Aggregated information is not used in such a form that would enable direct connection of any personal information to our visitors.

In some cases, Motorola Solutions (“Processor”), as part of its business relationship with a retail business or other business or government customer, may be asked to receive, gather, store, or analyze information about the users, consumers or potential consumers of that business or government organization. In such cases, the business or government organization (“Controller”) will be responsible for determining how the information will be used and for providing notice and taking any other legal steps with regard to the collection and use of such information. Motorola Solutions, will be subject to binding contractual obligations to: (i) only Process the Personal Data in accordance with our prior written instructions; and (ii) use measures to protect the confidentiality and security of the Personal Data; together with any additional requirements under applicable law.  We will process your data on the basis of our legitimate interest to recruit new employees or contractors.

**Information for Channel Partners**  
If you represent a Motorola Solutions channel partner, you may visit Motorola Solutions' sites intended specifically for channel partners. We may use information provided on that site to administer and develop our business relationship with you, the channel partner you represent, and channel partners generally. For instance, this may involve using your information to send you details of channel partner programs, including product offerings or special opportunities. It may also include sharing certain information with other channel partners (subject to any confidentiality obligations that may exist), or Motorola Solutions' customers or prospects. In connection with a particular transaction or program, we may also contact you as part of customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes.  We will process your data on the basis of performance of a contract to which you (as a representative of a Motorola Solutions channel partner) are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract.

**Information for Suppliers**  
If you represent a Motorola Solutions' supplier, you may visit Motorola Solutions' Web sites intended specifically for use by Motorola Solutions' suppliers. We may use the information provided on that site in connection with entering into or performing purchases, contracts, or other transactions with you or related business partners (such as customers). For example, this may include sharing information with other parts of Motorola Solutions, Motorola Solutions' channel partners, customers, shipping companies, financial institutions and postal or government authorities involved in fulfillment. It may also be used to administer and develop our relationship with you, the supplier you represent, and other Motorola Solutions' suppliers generally.

### Mobile Applications

**Mobile Applications and Use of Information in the Social Computing Environment**

Motorola Solutions also provides social computing tools on some of its Web sites to enable online sharing and collaboration among members who have registered to use them. These include forums, wikis, blogs and other social media platforms.

When registering to use these social computing tools, you may be asked to provide certain personal information. Registration information will be subject to and protected in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

After completing your registration and with your permission, any other content you voluntarily post, such as pictures, information, opinions, or any other type of personal information that you make available to other participants on these social platforms may be made available to others inside and outside Motorola Solutions.

If you do not wish this information to be made broadly available you can cancel your registration at any time.   However, you may not be able to participate on these social platforms once your cancel your registration.

### Third Party Websites

**Who is collecting the information?**

When you are on a Motorola Solutions site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Motorola Solutions, Inc., its subsidiaries and related companies. Additionally, if you purchase a product or other device requiring service, your personal information may be collected by a third party company working with Motorola Solutions. Motorola Solutions may also contract with third party companies to perform services for Motorola Solutions on its web site that require these companies to collect personal information (e.g. hosting a web site sweepstakes, promotion or survey, or selling software downloads, online job application).

In addition, Motorola Solutions' web sites may be operated by third parties, or may allow third party vendors to provide products and services directly to Motorola Solutions customers. Such relationships are designated with a "Provided By" or "Powered By" company legend or logo, or other similarly worded designation. If you desire to purchase a product or service from such third party, your personal information will be collected by the third-party company, and shared with Motorola Solutions. You may review the privacy practices of the third party either by clicking the link on the bottom of the page, or by clicking on the "Provided by Company" logo, which will take you to their web site. Additionally, when you purchase or download software applications from Motorola Solutions or a third-party, your personal information is shared with the software developer/licensor in order to register you as a licensed software user, and to permit them to provide you any required support. If you are concerned about the privacy policy of a certain developer or software company, you may contact them directly or visit their individual web sites. The Motorola Solutions web site may also contain various links to third-party web sites. These sites may provide additional information, goods, services and/or promotions. These sites are owned and operated independently of Motorola Solutions, and have their own separate privacy and data collection practices. Any information you provide to these web sites will be governed under the terms of their privacy policy, if any. Motorola Solutions has no responsibility or liability whatsoever for the independent actions or policies of these independent sites, and is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such sites..

### Cookies

**What about cookies?**

When you enter our site, our server may attach a small text file to your hard drive called a cookie.   A "cookie" is a text file containing small amounts of information which is downloaded to your device when you visit a website.  These cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that cookie. In some countries, including European Union Member States, this information may be considered personal data under applicable data protection laws. A cookie will in most cases only be attached to your hard drive if you have taken some form of action on our website(s) to accept cookies using the prominent banner notice.   However, note that where implied consent is permissible by law, your action taken to browse the website will constitute consent. Cookies help Motorola Solutions deliver a better web site experience to our users. Please refer to [allaboutcookies.org website](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) for more information about cookies.

We may also use cookies to measure traffic patterns, and which areas of the Motorola Solutions site you have visited, and your visiting patterns. This information collected by using a cookie is sometimes called "clickstream." We use this information to understand how our users navigate our site, and to determine common traffic patterns, including what site the user came from. We use this information to make site navigation and product recommendations, and to help redesign our site in order to make your experience on our site more efficient and enjoyable.

We may also use this information to better personalize the content, banner ads, and promotions that you and other users will see. This helps Motorola Solutions deliver you the content you want when you want it, in order for you to make better purchasing decisions. Motorola Solutions uses third parties to track user clickstreams. These third party companies use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, hardware/software information, cookie and session ID) and personally identifiable information (e.g., in some jurisdictions, IP address) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest or relevance to you.

You have choices with respect to cookies. We may Process your Personal Data through cookie technology, in accordance with this Cookie Statement.

### California Residents

**Privacy Rights of California Residents  
"Do Not Track"**

Please note that as described above ('What about Cookies?" section) you may be able to control the use of cookies through modification of your web browser preferences. Some web browsers may give you the ability to enable a "do not track" setting that sends a special signal to the websites you visit while browsing the internet. Activating the "do not track' setting is different from declining cookies in your browser settings. To learn more about Privacy Rights of California Residents, [click here](http://www.motorolasolutions.com/en_us/about/privacy-policy/california-privacy-rights.html).

### Use of Personal Data

**How is my personal information used?**

Motorola Solutions' primary goal in collecting personal information is to facilitate order processing, to communicate regarding business matters, to enable us to contact you if a problem arises with your order, or if there is some other need to reach you. Additionally, if you purchase a product or other device requiring service, your personal information may be used to obtain a credit report if necessary. Such information is required to complete a purchase transaction. This information may also be used to provide you with a customized experience on our site, which includes interactive communications and other services. The Motorola Solutions site may also contain optional registration, surveys and questionnaires asking for information, as well as several opportunities for visitors to ask questions. We use the information you provide to help us design and build better products, to customize your shopping experience, to work better with you as a channel partner, and to provide advice and purchase recommendations. If you do not provide information that we request, we may not be able to provide (or continue providing) relevant products or services.

We also use the information we collect to help target valuable marketing and advertising offers. This kind of advertising may be done with banner ads as well as promotional emails sent by Motorola Solutions, or by third parties under contract with Motorola Solutions. Motorola Solutions may also match user information with third party data to help us better understand our customers. Such marketing campaigns will be performed under direct marketing rules under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and applicable direct marketing rules under the Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations (“PECR”)

We may ask you for and collect personal information at other times, including when you enter a sweepstakes or contest; participate in a promotion or marketing campaign sponsored by Motorola Solutions or one of its business partners; when you want to find out about service offered in your area; when you complete surveys or other questionnaires; when you participate in a user forum or blog hosted by Motorola Solutions or one of its business partners; when you send an email to Motorola Solutions.

Motorola Solutions (and our Service Providers) may also collect information made publicly available through third-party platforms such as social media websites, online databases, or directories or other legitimately obtained information. This information may be governed by the privacy notice(s) provided by the third party at the time of collection.

If you do not wish to receive marketing communications you can opt out by visiting the Communications Preference Center. After you opt out, we will not send further promotional emails, but we may continue to contact you to the extent necessary for the purposes of any services that you have requested.

Motorola Solutions also conducts research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us when making a purchase, during a promotion, from surveys and from our server log files. We do this to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis so as to prevent identification of personal information relating to any one individual. Motorola Solutions may share this aggregated data with our business partners.

### Legal Basis

**On what legal basis does Motorola Solutions process my personal information?**

Motorola Solutions' legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

However, Motorola Solutions will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, Motorola Solutions may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

If Motorola Solutions asks you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information).

Similarly, if Motorola Solutions collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

### Sharing of Personal Data

**With whom does Motorola Solutions share my personal information?**

Except as outlined in this Statement or on our web sites, Motorola Solutions does not provide your personal information to third parties without your consent. Please note that, in special cases, we may need to share information without acquiring consent, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, or to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our sites' Terms of Use or may be violating Motorola Solutions' or other's rights or causing injury to or interference with Motorola Solutions' or others' property.

In addition, Motorola Solutions shares the information you provide with Motorola Solutions subsidiaries and related companies. If you or your company purchase a product or other device requiring service, your personal information is shared with the relevant service provider. Additionally, if you express an interest in a product requiring a particular type of service, Motorola Solutions may share your personal information with your local service provider in order to determine whether such service is available in your area.

Motorola Solutions may share your personal information with third-party business partners so that they may provide services to Motorola Solutions that are consistent with the terms of this Privacy Statement, and this web site (e.g. database management, sending targeted emails, software sales, and conducting sweepstakes and other promotions on behalf of Motorola Solutions). Motorola Solutions takes great pride in utilizing only reputable business partners. Motorola Solutions may also, on occasion, provide personal information to third-party businesses as part of a specific product, service, or promotion.

Motorola Solutions shares web site usage information about visitors to our web sites, who have received a targeted promotional campaign, with reputable third-party advertising companies for the purpose of targeting future campaigns and upgrading visitor information used in reporting statistics. For this purpose, we and our third-party advertising companies note some of the pages you visit on our web sites through the use of pixel tags (also called clear gifs). The information collected by our third-party advertising companies through the use of these pixel tags is not personally identifiable.

Motorola Solutions may share your personal information in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, consolidation or restructuring, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by or to another company.

Motorola Solutions may share your information if required to do so by law, court order, subpoena or other legal process; as requested by a governmental or law enforcement authority; or to enforce applicable Terms of Use.  We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or advisable.

### Mergers or Acquisitions or Sale

We may sell or buy other businesses or entities. In such event, we may transfer or assign the information we have collected as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control to another company. In such transactions, your personal Information may be included in the transferred business assets. Such company will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. You agree that we can accordingly assign, sell, license or transfer any personal information that you have provided to us to those third parties directly involved in the transfer or disposition of such assets.

Also, in the unlikely event of our bankruptcy or insolvency, your personal information may be included in the transferred assets to third parties.

### Your Choices

**What choices do I have regarding collection, use and distribution of my personal information?**

Motorola Solutions or its business partners may, from time to time, send you email or direct mail regarding our products and services. If you do not want to receive such information, simply tell us when you give us your personal information, or follow the directions contained on the mailing to remove your name from our mailing list(s).  Your communications preferences can be managed at the [Communications Preference Center](https://www.motorolasolutions.com/en_xu/preference-center-form.html). 

On certain types of Motorola Solutions promotions, we will ask for your email address in order to contact you in the event you have won a prize. When you participate in these types of promotions, you may receive promotion-related email. Occasionally these promotion-related email messages may include targeted advertisements. If you do not wish to receive such advertisements, you can choose not to participate in such promotions or contests.

Please note that by refusing to provide personal information or by denying or withdrawing consent to use personal information for purposes identified, you or your company may be unable to participate in certain programs or activities sponsored by Motorola Solutions.

Under the law of certain countries, you may also have the right to access (review, correct, amend or delete) your personal information by contacting Motorola Solutions. Individuals are responsible for providing Motorola Solutions with accurate and complete personal information, and for contacting Motorola Solutions if correction of such information is required. We will strive to keep information we hold about customers accurate.  

If you have established a "user profile" on a Motorola Solutions web site, you may change the information you provided by visiting that portion of the web site and resubmitting your information.

Please direct any questions concerning Motorola Solutions' privacy practices to [privacy1@motorolasolutions.com.](mailto:privacy1@motorolasolutions.com) Requests to unsubscribe from ("opt-out" of) communications from Motorola Solutions can be managed here. Inquiries or requests may be mailed to:  

Motorola Solutions, Inc. **  
Attention: Privacy Compliance Program  
**P.O. Box 59263  
Schaumburg, IL USA 60159-0263

### European Union (EU) Data Protection Rights

**What about my rights under EU law?**

Individuals whose personal information is collected and/or used in Europe have the rights described in our BCRs.

**What are your rights in relation to Personal Data**

Subject to applicable law, you may have a number of rights regarding the Processing of your Personal Data, including:

  * The right to request access to, or copies of your Personal Data that we Process or control, together with information regarding the nature, processing and disclosure of those Personal Data;
  * The right to request rectification of any inaccuracies in your Personal Data that we Process or control;
  * The right to request, on legitimate grounds  
      ◦  Erasure of your Personal Data that we Process or control; or  
      ◦  Restriction of Processing of your Personal Data that we Process or control;
  * The right to have your Personal Data that we Process or control transferred to another Controller, to the extent applicable;  

  * Where we Process your Personal Data on the basis of your consent, the right to withdraw that consent; and
  * The right to lodge complaints with a Data Protection Authority regarding the Processing of your Personal Data by us or on our behalf.

This does not affect your statutory rights.

Subject to applicable law, you may also have the following additional rights regarding the Processing of your Personal Data:

  * The right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, to the Processing of your Personal Data by us or on our behalf; and
  * The right to object to the Processing of your Personal Data, by us or on our behalf for direct marketing purposes.

To exercise one of more of these rights, or to ask a question about these rights or any other provision of this Policy, or about our Processing of your Personal Data, please use the contact details provided in the How To Contact Us section below.

### Information Security

**What about information security?**

When you place an order or provide personal information, we employ certain technical and organization security measures, such as encryption where appropriate. Encryption scrambles the information in your purchase, including your credit card number, so this information can only be viewed by Motorola Solutions. Motorola Solutions currently uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology, where appropriate, for Internet-based transactions.

However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we have taken appropriate steps to protect your personal information, Motorola Solutions cannot ensure or otherwise warrant the security of any information you provide to us or from our Web site, and therefore you use our site at your own risk.

### International Data Transfers

**Where will my personal information be transferred?**

As a global company Motorola Solutions has international sites and users all over the world.  The personal information you provide may be transmitted, used, stored and otherwise processed outside of the country where you submitted that information, including jurisdictions that may not have data privacy laws that provide equivalent protection to such laws in your home country, including primarily the United States where are global headquarters is located. Whenever Motorola Solutions handles personal information, regardless of where this occurs, we take appropriate steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Use, this Privacy Statement and all applicable laws and regulations. Our [BCRs](https://www.motorolasolutions.com/content/dam/msi/docs/business/_documents/static_files/Motorola_Solutions_BCR_Policy.pdf) govern transfers between our group companies and require all group companies to protect personal information they process from the EEA in accordance with European Union data protection law.

We have implemented similar appropriate safeguards, such as entering into the European Commission's Standard Contractual Clauses, with our third party service providers and partners and further details can be provided on request.

### Retention

**For how long will Motorola Solutions keep my personal information?**

We apply a general rule of keeping personal information only for as long as required to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected.  However, in some circumstances we may retain personal information for longer periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax and accounting requirements.

In specific circumstances we may also retain your personal information for longer periods of time so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

### Children's Privacy

**What about my child's privacy?**

Web sites operated by or on behalf of Motorola Solutions, Inc. and its world-wide affiliated companies and subsidiaries are intended for use by persons age 13 and over or as required by local law. Motorola Solutions does not seek to collect information about children under the age of 13. No information should be submitted to or posted on Motorola Solutions' web sites by users under 13 years of age. If a child under the age of 13 submits personal information to Motorola Solutions' web sites, we delete the information as soon as we discover it was provided by a child under 13 years of age and do not use it for any purpose. Motorola Solutions encourages parents to take an active role in their children's use of the Internet, and to inform them of the potential dangers of providing information about themselves over the Internet.

**This Privacy Statement is subject to change. The last content update was made on May 21, 2018**
